Guide to the Ernestine Evans Papers, 1890-1968
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Personal, 1907-1968, Undated
  Personal documents relating to Evans' life, including mementos and ephemera, address books and journals, medical and financial documents, and government-issued documents, such as passports can be found in this series. Also included in this series are documents relating to Evans' old age care, funeral, and memorial services. There is also a small collection of documents related to three other parties: real estate and financial documents regarding the Hirschl family, as well as personal documents belonging to Louise F. Lee and Colin Landin.
  - Autobiographical Writings and Guggenheim Fellowship Application, Undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Ephemera and Mementos, 1941-1962, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 12 to 13)
  - Address Books, Undated, (23 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1 to 23)
  - Address book, Undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Journal, Undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Postcards, Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Postcards to Evans, 1907-1966, Undated, (5 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 4 to 8)
  - Contacts, 1965-1966, Undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Contacts--UN Telephone Directory, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Financial
    - Banking, 1941-1967 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Leases, 1946-1961 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - General, 1941-1967 Undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Flaherty Films, 1946-1965 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Medical documents, 1953-1965, Undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Passports, 1949-1957 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Funeral and Memorial Service for Evans, 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Others
    - Flaherty, Robert--Memorial Documents, 1948-1951 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Hirschl, Jessie [Heckman]--financial documents, 1892-1965 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Landin, Colin--Correspondence, 1950-1954, Undated (4 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 6 to 9)
    - Landin, Colin--General, 1951-1956 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Lee, Louise, 1945-1956 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Weil, Elsie--Journal, Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Series IV: Visual material, 1890s-1963, Undated
  This series contains a wide array of photographs, prints, drawings and watercolor paintings. Among the large collection of photographs are a small number of images of Evans; images of schoolchildren by the renowned photographer Gordon Parks; images and manuscripts from the Magnum News Service; photographs and picture postcards from many countries around the world, including Russia, Mongolia, India and Mexico; and film stills from documentaries by Evans' friend and colleague, Robert Flaherty.
  Other visual material includes unattributed life-drawings as well as drawings and paintings by children, perhaps dating to Evans' time at the Whitney Studio Club; large-format illustrated maps and posters; illustrations and page proofs, likely from books that Evans commissioned and edited while working as a literary agent; and a smattering of additional material.
  - Photographs
    - Ernestine Evans, 1890s-1950s (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Astor Place Riots and Rammed Earth Construction, Undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Robert Flaherty documentary film stills, Undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - India and Africa, various, Undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Magnum News Service Photographs: Algeria, Space Exploration, Moscow, Iraq, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Parks, Gordon--Students of P.S. 186 in Harlem, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - India--News Stock Images, Undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Individuals, Undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Mexico, Undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - “Moscow Strikes Back,” Undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Miller, Lee--Unidentified Sitter, Undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Southeast Asia, Undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - U.S.S.R., Undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - General, Undated, (5 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 10 to 14)
    - India, Undated, (11 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 1 to 11)
    - General, Undated, (12 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 12 to 23)
  - Visual Material--Oversize
    - Drawings--Hewes, Alanson--Life-Drawings, Undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Illustrations and Page Proofs--Jones, Lombard C.--Papermaking Cartoons, Undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Illustrations and Page Proofs--Kimball, Marie-- The Martha Washington Cookbook, Undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Paintings--Watercolor Landscapes by Children, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Photographs, Undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Posters--British Information Services, Undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Relief Prints, Undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Reproductions, Undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - General visual material, unattributed, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 10 to 11)
  - Visual Material--General
    - Book Art, Undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Cartoon Cells--“Rumpus,” Undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Data Visualizations--Scott Air Force Base, circa 1945 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Drawings
      - Children’s, Undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Craig, John, Undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Hewes, Alanson, Undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Pen, Undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Pencil and Charcoal, Undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - General, Undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Illustrations--Japanese, Undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Illustrations and Page Proofs
      - Hewes, Alanson, Undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Lee, Charles--An Almanac of Reading, 1940 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Nautical Motifs-Mexican children, Undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Scherf, Margaret--The Case of the Kippered Corpse, Undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - Various, Undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Paintings--Watercolor, Undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Paintings--Other, Undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Posters--British Empire, Cuba, U.S. Office of Emergency Management, Undated (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Relief Prints, Undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Reproductions, Undated, (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 20 to 21)
    - General, Undated (Box 28, Folder 22)